rubytuesday.com 2013-06-27

# Privacy Policy - Ruby Tuesday

## Privacy Policy and Terms of Use

Ruby Tuesday, Inc. ("Ruby Tuesday") is very sensitive to the privacy concerns of our web site visitors, and we want to make sure your online experience is safe and enjoyable. Any information collected from you is used to provide you with a broad range of services. Individual information is not gathered except on a voluntary basis. Depending on the service you are accessing, you may be asked at times to provide information such as name, e-mail address, and opinion and concerns about certain products and services. Ruby Tuesday uses its web sites as communication tools. We collect information which identifies your mode of communication, such as which browser you use, the state in which your Internet server is located, how long you visit and where on our web site you view. This information is used to update and enhance your visit to Ruby Tuesday web sites.

Ownership of any information you provide will be held by Ruby Tuesday alone. We do not sell ownership of this data to any other company or organization nor transfer information to competitors. Information about your visit is used internally at Ruby Tuesday.

**Opt-In Email Communications**  
There is an optional section of our web site where input forms require your name, phone number, mailing address, e-mail address, and other personal information. This form provides the ability to opt-in to receiving future emails of any sort from Ruby Tuesday and its affiliates. If you opt-in to receiving email communications from us, then we may send information to you on our products or services and the products and services of our affiliates.

You may review and change your information with us at any time by clicking on the “update profile” link on the site or similar found at the bottom of emails sent via our system, or by contacting us at [GuestServices@rubytuesday.com](mailto:guestservices@rubytuesday.com). 

To opt-out from having any provided information used for email communications from us, please click on the opt-out (unsubscribe) link in any message you receive from us. This will allow you to unsubscribe or update your message preferences. Alternately, you may contact us at [GuestServices@rubytuesday.com](mailto:guestservices@rubytuesday.com).

We want you and your family to be free of concern while visiting our web sites. For this reason, we never knowingly request personally identifiable information from children. This position is consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.

**Cookies**  
When you visit our website, we send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your computer or other device that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to track web analytics information including user trends and search preferences, improve the quality of our services, and for storing and retrieving user preferences. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie so you have the chance to accept it and can set your browser to turn off cookies. No personally identifying information from you will be collected as part of these cookies.

**Logs & IP Addresses**  
When you access our site, we automatically record and store information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

At times we will use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. We also may track browser types to help us understand our visitors' needs related to our web site design.

**Links**  
Sometimes there may be links on our web site that allow you to leave our site. We do not control the links or these web sites and we are not responsible for the contents of any linked site. The inclusion of any link does not imply our endorsement of that web site. The use and/or privacy policy of a linked web site may be different from that of Ruby Tuesday web sites. In any case, we cannot be responsible for the use of your information by linked sites.

**Personal Information**  
Although unlikely, we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. If requested as part of a legal proceeding, we will provide this information upon receipt of the appropriate documentation. 

**Third Party Collection of Information**  
We use a third party to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. The third party may also collect anonymous information about your visits to our web site. This is primarily accomplished through the use of a technology device, commonly referred to as a Web Beacon or an Action Tag, which we place on various web pages within our web site that allows the third party to collect anonymous information. The third party may use information about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide ads about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by the third party, [click here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy_cookies.html). The third party reports the anonymous data that they collect on our behalf back to us, which we link to our customers' personally identifiable information for the purposes of better serving you. When we merge this data, it is treated under this policy as personally identifiable information as described above.

**Terms of Use**  
By using the Ruby Tuesday web site, you agree to be bound by our Terms of Use. Ruby Tuesday reserves the right to make changes to our Terms of Use at any time.

By using the Ruby Tuesday web sites, you expressly agree that the materials and information you find on this web site are provided "AS IS," without warranty of any kind, either express or implied, including without limitation any warranty for information, services or products and any implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose. Some states do not allow the exclusion of implied warranties, so the above exclusion may not apply to you.

By using the Ruby Tuesday web sites, you agree to use the sites for only lawful purposes. You agree to do nothing that could compromise the security of the sites, render the sites inaccessible or otherwise cause damage to the site or their content. 

By using this web site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. We may also change the Privacy Policy from time to time, so please be sure to visit this web site often to see if anything has changed. If we post changes and you continue to use the web site, you will be deemed to have agreed to the changes.

Under no circumstances will Ruby Tuesday or its subsidiaries, affiliates, designees, officers, directors, employees, attorneys, agents, insurers, successors or assignees be liable for any direct, indirect, special or consequential damages that result from your use of or inability to use the Ruby Tuesday web site, including but not limited to your reliance on information obtained from this web site that results in mistakes, omissions, interruptions, deletion or corruption of files, viruses, delays in operation or transmission or any failure of performance.

All content on the Ruby Tuesday web site is protected by copyright, trademark and/or other proprietary rights, and these rights are valid and protected in all forms, medias and technologies, whether existing now or developed in the future. You may not copy, modify, remove, delete, augment, add to, publish, transmit, transfer, sell, lease, rent, create derivative works from, or in any way exploit the content of this web site, in whole or in part. The use of our trademarks, service marks and logos without our written permission is strictly prohibited.

**Safe Harbor Data Privacy Notice**  
Ruby Tuesday, Inc. ("Ruby Tuesday") adheres to the Safe Harbor Principles published by the U.S. Department of Commerce (the "Safe Harbor Principles") with respect to personal information (as defined below) it receives from the European Union.

Ruby Tuesday will respond to your request to access or delete personal information within 30 days as is required under the EU Safe Harbor program.

This notice outlines our general policy and practices for implementing the Safe Harbor Principles, including the type of information to which this notice applies, how we use personal information, and the choices individuals have regarding our use of, and their ability to correct, that personal information. If there is any conflict between the policies in this notice and the Safe Harbor Principles, the Safe Harbor Principles will govern.

This notice applies to all personal information we handle, including on-line (except as noted below), and manually processed data. For purposes of this notice, "personal information" means data that: is transferred from the European Union to the United States; is recorded in any form; and is about, or pertains to, a specific individual who is identified in, or is identifiable from, the data.

"Sensitive information" is a subcategory of personal information. Sensitive information is defined as personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or the sex life of the individual. Sensitive information also includes personal information received from a third party where the third party treats and identifies it as sensitive.

### Safe Harbor Principles Regarding Personal Information

**Notice and Choice**  
We notify individuals about the personal information we collect from them, how we use it, and how to contact us with privacy concerns. We obtain personal information only as permitted by the Safe Harbor Principles or with the consent of the individual affected. Consent for personal information to be collected, used, and/or disclosed in certain ways may be required in order for an individual to obtain or use our services. To the extent permitted under the Safe Harbor, we reserve the right to process personal information in the course of providing professional services to our clients without the knowledge of individuals involved.

**Disclosures and Transfers**  
We do not disclose personal information to third parties, except when one or more of the following conditions is true:

  * We have the individual's permission to make the disclosure;
  * The disclosure is permitted by law or mandatory professional standards;
  * The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or other disposition of all or part of our business or assets;
  * The personal information to be disclosed is publicly available;
  * The party to whom the disclosure is made controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with Ruby Tuesday;
  * The disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or maintenance of legal claims; or
  * The disclosure is to persons or entities for whom we are providing services, provided the disclosure is consistent with the purpose for which the personal information was obtained.

We will comply with the Safe Harbor Principles with respect to disclosures of sensitive information, including, when applicable, obtaining the explicit consent of the individual prior to disclosing sensitive information to a third party or using sensitive information for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. Transfers of information permitted under this notice, either to third parties or within Ruby Tuesday, include the transfer of data from one jurisdiction to another, such as transfers to and from the United States of America.

**Data Security, Integrity, and Access**  
We employ physical, electronic, and managerial measures, including education and training of our personnel, designed to provide the personal information in our possession with reasonable protection from accidental loss or destruction, improper use, alteration, or disclosure. Personal information collected or displayed through a web site is protected in transit by industry standard encryption processes. However, we cannot guarantee the security of personal information accessible on or transmitted via the Internet.

We process personal information in ways compatible with the purpose for which the personal information was collected, or as otherwise authorized by the individual. To the extent necessary for such purposes, we take reasonable steps to make sure that personal information is accurate, complete, current, and otherwise reliable with regard to its intended use.

If an individual becomes aware that personal information we maintain about that individual is inaccurate, or if an individual would like to update or review his or her personal information, the individual may contact us using the contact information below. As a security precaution, we may request that the individual provide identifying information such as name, address, birth date, and/or social security number. In addition, we may limit or deny access to personal information where providing such access would be unreasonably burdensome or expensive in the circumstances, or as otherwise permitted by the Safe Harbor Agreement. In some circumstances, we may charge a reasonable fee, where warranted, for access to personal information.

**Accountability and Enforcement**  
We established a program to monitor our adherence to the Safe Harbor Principles and to address questions and concerns regarding our adherence. This program will include a statement, at least once a year, signed by our authorized representative, verifying our adherence to the Safe Harbor Principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns with us using the contact information below.

With respect to any dispute relating to this notice that cannot be resolved through our internal processes, we will cooperate with competent European Union data protection authorities and comply with the advice of such authorities. In the event that we or such authorities determine that we did not comply with this notice, we will take appropriate steps to address any adverse effects and to promote future compliance.

**Amendment**  
We may amend this notice from time to time by posting a revised notice on this Web site, or a similar Web site that replaces this Web site. If we amend the notice, the new notice will apply to personal information previously collected only insofar as the rights of the individual affected are not reduced. So long as we profess to adhere to the Safe Harbor Principles, we will not amend this notice in a manner inconsistent with the Safe Harbor Principles.

**Information Subject to Other Policies**  
We are committed to following the Safe Harbor Principles for all personal information, as that term is defined herein. Other information we receive may be subject to policies that may differ in some respects from the policies set forth in this notice. Certain of our Web sites have their own privacy policies that apply specifically to those Web sites. Those policies may be accessed through the Web sites in question. Information relating to present or former Ruby Tuesday personnel is subject to our policies concerning personnel data privacy, which are available to present and former Ruby Tuesday personnel upon request. Information obtained from or relating to clients or former clients is further subject to the terms of any privacy commitment made to the client, any agreements with the client, and/or any applicable laws and professional standards.

**Contact Information**  
For further information, please contact us:

**Ruby Tuesday, Inc.  
150 West Church Avenue  
Maryville, Tennessee 37801  
USA  
Phone: (865) 379-5700 **
